[FRIDA humming]
[gasps]
Before we go on, are there
any questions up to this point?
Hm? Appears Lucian's
absent again today.
Has anyone seen him?
[TATE gasps]
Professor!
Yes? What is it, Tate?
[TATE]
Lucian's-- Well, you see, uh...
He has a cold.
A cold? I'm sorry to hear.
Right. After the lecture,
I think I'll pay him a visit.
No! You don't have to do that!
You see, Lucian and I share
the same dormitory room,
so I'm looking after him.
Interesting. Well,
that's a relief to hear.
[CLERK 05A]
Tate Percival and Lucian Atwood?
I'll find the information
for you right away, sir.
[WILLIAM] Lucian is the heir
to the Atwood viscountcy.
A lineage that goes
back over two centuries.
Similar to Tate's.
So both of them are heirs
to aristocratic families.
[TATE] I can't cover
for you much longer.
Honestly, where'd
you disappear to?
[sneezes]
On top of everything,
now I've got a cold.
[knocking]
[TATE]
Yes?
[gasps] Professor Moriarty!
Why're you here?
That was an
impressive sneeze, Tate.
I heard it clearly
through the door.
Then again, you've been
looking after Lucian.
Perhaps you caught his cold?
Uhh...
[TATE stammers]
Th-That's probably it.
Professor!
Wait. I wouldn't--
There's no need for that!
[TATE gasps]
[WILLIAM] This bed hasn't
been slept in for some time.
[TATE]
Well...
I suggest you start
talking, and quickly.
[TATE yelps]
Despite my demeanor,
at this moment, I'm more cross
than you could possibly imagine.
[whimpers]
[TATE sighs]
Do you mean to tell me that
Lucian hasn't been to the
dormitory in three days?
Sneaking out of the dorms and
being gone all night
isn't anything new.
But he's always back
the next morning.
He should've returned by now.
I was worried, so I went
down to check at the pub.
There's a waitress
there named Frida
who Lucian is
absolutely mad about.
If he was spending
the night anywhere,
I would've expected it
to be at her place.
- -[TATE gasps]
- -[HOSTESS 05A] Piss off!
[WILLIAM] That explains it--
at least how you got your cold.
However, such a harsh welcome
and without warning is odd.
Leads me to believe
there may have been
some trouble beforehand.
[TATE] Look, Professor,
he may be a foolhardy gadabout,
but he has a good heart.
I'll say this,
it doesn't matter what
he's got himself mixed up in,
I just want to bring him home.
It sounds to me like
you're very concerned
about Lucian's wellbeing.
Of course, I am, sir!
Why say "of course"?
[TATE]
I mean, because...
...Lucian is my friend!
[WILLIAM]
From here on,
I think it's best if you
stay out of the matter.
Leave this to me;
I'll deal with Lucian.
Uh, yes, sir.
[WILLIAM]
And Tate...
[TATE]
Hm?
No fortune's greater than the
bond shared between friends.
[DUDLEY]
Professor Moriarty, I presume?
[WILLIAM]
And you are?
The name's Dudley Bale,
a humble administrative
assistant for the university.
I've seen you from time-to-time
strolling about
the campus grounds.
Please, forgive my manners.
Introductions are past due.
I noticed you coming
from the dormitories.
Is something amiss
with one of your students?
[WILLIAM] Possibly. I went
to pay Lucian Atwood a visit.
He's been absent from my
lectures for several days,
so I wanted to check up on him.
Did you catch the
rogue nursing a hangover?
The issue is
finding him actually.
According to his roommate,
he hasn't shown his
face for three days.
Staying out overnight
without permission?
Not uncommon for these boys,
but rules are rules.
Then again, why don't we look
the other way this one time?
Don't want to
come down too hard.
Otherwise, we're bound
to start a rebellion.
But still,
we can agree that three days
is slightly irregular.
Perhaps we should
notify the police.
Normally, I would agree,
but this could be
a very delicate situation.
See, Lucian is
the son of nobility,
and any brush with the law
would reflect poorly on
the family name.
[WILLIAM] Then what?
You'd have us drop the matter?
Don't misunderstand me.
I have connections
with the local police
and could ask them to look into
his disappearance discreetly.
Please, allow me to handle this
to avoid damaging
the family's name.
So, that settles it?
There's no need to be concerned.
[WILLIAM]
This is the pub where
Tate received his
not-so-warm welcome.
[door opens]
We're closed. Come back later.
[WILLIAM]
I realize it's early.
However, I'm not
here to buy a drink.
I'd like to have
a word with you.
[HOSTESS 05A]
Hmm.
[HOSTESS 05A] Just for
talkin' about a dead girl?
This is quite the tip.
You a newspaper
reporter or what?
Nothing like that.
My name's William James Moriarty
and I teach at
Dunham University.
You're a college professor?
If there's an issue
with a student's conduct,
it's my duty as an educator
to set things right.
In order to do that, first,
I must collect all the necessary
facts pertaining to the matter.
[HOSTESS 05A]
Mm.
[HOSTESS 05A] What can I say?
Frida was a wonderful girl.
She loved dancing.
And when she smiled,
the entire room would light up.
A real flower, that one.
Which makes what happened
all the more tragic.
According to the old man
who lived under the bridge,
last thing she was doing was
singin' and dancin' before
she fell into the river.
I wonder what she
was singin' about.
See, Professor,
Frida and this missing student
of yours had fallen in love.
Thing is, he's a
big-shot aristocrat.
Not the same class as us.
I'm sure she thought
he was just looking for
a good time at the beginning.
But then, he proposed
marriage to her.
[FRIDA gasps]
I want to spend the rest of my
days dancing with one person.
You, Frida.
Would you mind being
my dance partner
forever?
[FRIDA giggles]
Not one bit.
[HOSTESS 05A] I tried to talk
her out of it... at first.
Then she told me that
she was with child.
And after seeing that blissful
expression on her face,
I couldn't raise any objections.
However, before long,
he entered the picture.
I don't know exactly what
he said to Frida that night.
But...
[HOSTESS 05A]
...it was at that moment I knew.
She'd been abandoned.
Even so, she
gathered herself up,
said she would raise
the child by herself.
And then...
I just asked you to
recount a harrowing tale.
Please forgive me.
Thanks to your assistance,
I'm now fully aware
of what must be done.
Though, sadly, I'm unable
to bring the girl back.
I can promise you this:
The matter will be resolved
in a way that I hope
brings you closure.
[HOSTESS 05A]
You forgot something.
In case you're curious,
Frida's buried
in a potter's field.
Unfortunately, even if the
girls and I pooled our earnings,
we still couldn't afford
a proper headstone for her.
Listen, mate. If you
feel any pity for the girl,
use that money. Place some
flowers on her grave.
[DUDLEY] You have the
package I entrusted to you?
Yes, and as for the quality
of the newest shipment,
it appears to be quite potent.
He's resting comfortably inside.
[DUDLEY] Are we feeling more
composed today, Lucian?
[LUCIAN]
Frida?
Unfortunately, the girl had a
slight accident and perished.
Plunged right into the river.
Wait, what? I don't understand.
I made her a promise.
[DUDLEY] I know you're having
difficulty processing this.
I think it's best if you stay
until your emotional
wounds are healed.
Please, there's
no need to be hasty.
[LUCIAN grunts]
[WILLIAM]
Louis.
I'd like you to send
those two a telegram for me.
Then you mean...
[WILLIAM] The time has come
for us to make our move.
- -[knocking]
- -[MORAN groans]
[FRED]
Excuse me, sir. A telegram.
[MORAN chuckles]
The brothers came all the way
down to the station to greet me.
It's been far too long,
Colonel Moran.
So we finally getting started?
That's the reason you
sent me the telegram, innit?
Now, now, all in good time.
There's an order
to these things.
On that note, I trust your
skills are as sharp as ever.
You have to ask? Hm?
If it isn't Fred!
Haven't lost that
sunny disposition, I see.
I requested that
he come before you
to handle a certain errand.
Did you locate what I asked for?
[FRED]
Mm. I checked the hospital
and found him in the
brothel two doors down.
Thanks to the opium, he's not in
his right mind, least not yet.
[WILLIAM] It appears the
stage is ready to be set.
Now this job wasn't requested
by a client, but still...
[WILLIAM] Gentlemen,
let's deliver some punishment.
[MORAN]
Sadly, tonight's not your night.
Wow! You're so good,
Mister Moran!
What can I say, chaps? Looks
like I'm on a winning streak.
No one's that lucky!
Unless they've been
cheatin' this whole time!
Fools all say the same thing
when they're down on their luck.
And they were the blokes who
died first on the battlefield.
So, Mister Moran, sir,
now that you've made
all that money at cards,
would you care to have
a different sort of fun?
Sounds smashing. Your
room on the second floor?
[BARMAID 05B] That's right. You
were quick to catch my meaning.
[MORAN] And you were
quick to catch my eye
when I stepped through the door.
[BARMAID 05B]
Right this way, Romeo.
[LUCIAN grunts]
How'd I get here?
[DUDLEY]
There you are, Lucian!
[DUDLEY panting]
Sir Dudley?
Now wait. Let's discuss this.
You could've asked us
to meet somewhere closer!
What was the meaning
of that letter?!
You're not actually going
to confess your crime!
That's ludicrous!
And after everything
I did to clean up after you!
For that matter, how did you
even get out of your room?
You cleaned up after me?
[DUDLEY]
Of course!
Why'd you have to
be so bloody careless
and get that common
barmaid pregnant?
Can you even imagine
the effort I went through?!
[LUCIAN gasps]
Frida?
[DUDLEY]
You are a nobleman!
You shouldn't have
gotten involved
with some backwater dishrag
like her in the first place!
Surely you can see that!
When the pen slips,
you throw out the paper,
not the pen!
It's the same way for people!
There's no changing it!
That's the way the
aristocratic world operates!
But I was supposed
to marry Frida.
[DUDLEY]
That'll be quite enough of that!
Now hold your tongue
and do exactly as I say!
[FRIDA humming]
[LUCIAN gasps]
My love...
[screams] It's impossible!
You're dead!
I killed you! I pumped
you full of opium,
then you plunged to
your death in the river!
What?
At last, the truth from
the culprit's own mouth.
The confession of
an unpardonable sin.
[DUDLEY]
What? Professor Moriarty?
Right, Fred. That'll do.
Very well.
You're a man.
The fog is especially
heavy this evening.
Combined with his slight build,
he pulled off the illusion
spectacularly.
Hold on,
you wrote me that letter asking
to meet here, not Lucian!
Guilty as charged.
I'm the architect responsible
for designing this plot.
But introductions are past due.
I'm William James Moriarty,
Crime Consultant.
[DUDLEY] What do you
mean "Crime Consultant"?
And why are you
dressed like that?!
[WILLIAM] Mister Bale,
I've done some research on you.
In addition to working
for the university,
you're also the owner
of several hospitals
or should I say brothels?
And is there a crime
against being a businessman?
Is that what you're calling it?
Your hospitals
served as a front,
which allowed you to order
large quantities of opiates
without arousing
anyone's suspicions.
After you were fully supplied,
you transformed the cellars of
your brothels into opium dens.
You lure the sons of
aristocrats into vice and sin,
then demand their parents
purchase your silence
unless they want those deeds to
become public knowledge.
Like a fire brigade that
goes around creating blazes,
then offering your services.
You are a different
class of despicable.
Hah! You have all
the answers, don't you?
Then go ahead and
turn me over to the police
and see what happens.
[WILLIAM]
I have no intention of that.
Your claim of having influence
with the local authorities
was not entirely unfounded.
So then what are
you going to do?
[WILLIAM]
I won't do anything.
But you, overcome with the guilt
of Miss Macaulay's death,
will dance yourself
into a frenzy
before taking your own life.
What?! Me, take my own life?!
You're a bit
touched in the head.
Why would I ever?
[DUDLEY squeaks]
Huh?! What the--?!
[MORAN chuckles]
[DUDLEY yelping]
You've got quite
the lively step there.
I've no doubt you'll prove to be
an adequate match for
your dance partner.
[shrieks]
[DUDLEY panting]
[WILLIAM] I don't think
you need any introduction.
Who are you?!
Stop! Get away from me!
[yelps]
[gasps]
[screams]
[LUCIAN cries]
[MORAN]
Good on him.
The kid erected
a fine tombstone.
A love deemed impossible
because of class.
Yeah. In a word, tragedy.
Both Frida and he were victims
of the country's
societal structure.
But in a different world,
the two of them would
have found happiness.
A tragedy, indeed...
[WILLIAM]
...and avoidable.
Which is why we must
dismantle the system.
[MORAN] Next time
on Moriarty the Patriot  .
"The NOAHTIC Act 1."